# Angel Ramsés Hernández Fonseca

Tuxtla Gutierrez, Chiapas | ib.angelrhdz@gmail.com | +52 9611729179 https://www.linkedin.com/in/angelhernandezfonseca

## **Professional profile**

QA Tester with foundational knowledge in software quality principles and tools such as JIRA, POSTMAN, and Android Studio. I have a solid engineering background, with a master's degree in engineering and a bachelor's degree in biomedical engineering. With 3 years of experience, I have developed strong skills in attention to detail, technical diagnostics and problem-solving in high-pressure environments. Additionally, I have basic knowledge of Python, computer networking and systems, enabling me to effectively tackle challenges related to software testing.

#### **Technical Skills**

Manual testing (Basics) | Checklist (Proficent) | Test Planning (Basics) | Documentation (Basics) | Bug report (Proficent) | Mobile Testing (Basics) | Android Studio (Basics) | API Testing (Basics) | GUI Testing (Basics) | Regression Testing (Basics) | JIRA (Basics) | Postman (Basics) | SQL (Basics) | Pyhton (Basics) | VS Code (Basics) | JSON (Basics) | Figma (Proficent) | Command Line (Basics) | Bash (Basics) | Git (Basics) | Chrome DevTools (Basics) | Google Sheets (Proficent) | Google Docs (Proficent) | Word (Proficent) | Excel (Proficent) | Draw.io (Proficent) | Inkscape (Basics) | Lightshot (Proficent)

# **Experience**

#### Biomedical Engineer, Fmedical - Chiapas, México

September 2023 – September 2024

- Diagnosed issues in medical equipment, saving the company nearly 100,000 pesos.
- Identified problems in the usage processes of medical equipment to safeguard its condition.
- Designed protocols for the use of medical equipment, thus reducing incidents related to its usage.
- Repaired medical equipment under tight deadlines and in high-pressure environments to ensure medical care for the population.

Service Engineer, Engineering Medical Systems – Chiapas, México

November 2021 – September 2023

- Documented failures found in medical equipment, detailing the issues thoroughly.
- Identified the lack of tools and methods for proper maintenance, improving customer service.
- Applied knowledge of networks and operating systems to install medical equipment.
- Used software such as Excel, Sheets, Docs, Word, and PowerPoint to create company documentation.

#### **Projects**

#### UrbanRoutes | Mobility App | TripleTen | 2024

Github Repository

- Inspected system requirements
- Created diagrams to represent the information from the requirements..
- Identified gray areas in the documentation.
- Created a checklist and test cases for the app's GUI design and functionality.
- Prepared detailed bug reports in JIRA.
- Wrote a comprehensive report summarizing the findings in tested sections of the app

#### Urban Grocers | App for ordering groceries | TripleTen | 2024

Github Repository

- Analyzed the application's requirements and documentation.
- Found multiple gray areas in the documentation.
- Designed a checklist to cover parts of the app's functionality.

- Made HTTP requests using POSTMAN to test the app's functionality.
- Applied basic knowledge of networking and REST architecture to understand the behavior of responses.
- Created bug reports in JIRA for the multiple issues found.

## Urban Lunch | App for Ordering from Different Restaurants | TripleTen | 2024

Github Repository

- Analyzed the mobile app requirements, finding test cases and gray areas.
- Designed a checklist with both positive and negative test cases.
- Tested the application using the Android Device Emulator from Android Studio.
- Created bug reports in Jira based on the findings in the app.
- Created a bug report outlining recommendations for the developers to improve the app.

## **Education**

#### TripleTen QA Engineer Bootcamp

Julio 2024– Present

• QA Engineer | Online

Universidad de Ciencia y Tecnología Descartes

September 2021– December

2023 | Graduated

• Master in Science of Engineering | Tuxtla Gutierrez, Chiapas

Universidad Politécnica de Chiapas

August 2017– August 2021 |

Graduated

• Bachelor's Degree in Biomedical Engineering | Suchiapa, Chiapas

Canadian Center

August 2018– August 2020 |

Graduated

• English Course | Tuxtla Gutiérrez

#### Languages

Spanish | English (B1)